# Stephen Pedrosa Eilert

Cellphone: +1 (669) 226-7520

Email: contact@stepheneilert.com
Github: github.com/outworlder

## Summary

Sofware developer with 19 years of experience in a variety of projects for customers in the US and abroad. Experience with the full software development lifecycle, from requirements, design, development, testing, deployment, and system administration. Highly motivated by projects that challenge the technological status-quo. Somewhat paradoxically, likes to work closer to the machine, but also at the high levels of abstraction provided by functional languages. Follows with interest new technology developments, and will learn interesting technologies even when they are not directly relevant to the current work.

## Education

• BSc. Computer Science, Universidade Federal do Ceará, 2008.

## Professional Experience

#### 1. Hewlett Packard Enterprise, 2021 - Present

Distinguished Technologist. Architected the 'one-click' solution, which enables one-touch provisioning of complex Kubernetes clusters with their infrastructure (networking, databases, security) in a modular way, which works in AWS, GCP, and Azure. Responsible for the architecture of the Common Cloud Platform, used internally by multiple business units. Provides technical guidance for several teams in the company.

#### 2. Aruba Networks, a Hewlett Packard Enterprise Company, 2015 - 2021

Systems Software Engineer - Devops. Joined the Aruba Devops organization to work on automation. Improved the existing scripts to completely remove manual provisioning steps and human decision-making. This turned an activity that required multiple people across two timezones and at least one month to complete into a single-person, 20-minute job. Created the 'ClusterDB' - a single source of truth for all automation activities. Won company awards for his role in solving the technical issues that enabled a successful deployment of the Aruba Central product in China.

#### 3. Hewlett Packard Enterprise, 2015 - 2016

Systems Software Engineer. Joined the Openstack Neutron team, to work upstream. Delivered enhancements to Neutron to support VMWare ESX's distributed virtual switch (vDS). Fixed issues and was in charge of maintenance of the internal CI servers (Jenkins). Focus shifted to HP's Helion Openstack (HOS), backporting patches, fixing CI issues, and adding features and bugfixes to its Ansible-based installer.

#### 4. Hewlett-Packard Brazil, 2014 - 2015

Software engineer, working with an experienced team to develop a high-profile platform that handles printer monitoring and supplies. Technologies range from .NET desktop and web apps, printer communication protocols, and single-page web applications in Javascript/Backbone.js. Emphasis on code quality, with mandatory code reviews, high code test coverage and continuous integration.

Stephen Pedrosa Eilert

#### 5. Instituto Atlântico, 2013 - 2014

Software developer and tech lead on contract for Hewlett-Packard.

#### 6. Guilda (founder) / Codeminer 42, 2012 - 2013

Co-founded a company to develop Mobile (iOS and Android), C++ (with Qt), and Ruby on Rails applications for customers. Also provided consulting services and developed a cloud-based continuous integration system (currently discontinued) – one of the first in the market to use LXC containers. Acquired by Codeminer42.

#### 7. DETRAN-CE, 2010 - 2012

Software Engineer. Web systems in Ruby on Rails, consuming data from PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Cassandra. Development of a fingerprint recognition platform using libfprint, in both C and Python. Creation of a high-performance middleware application in C to broker communication between internal and external systems with the government's mainframe.

#### 8. Instituto Atlântico, 2004 - 2009

Developer and technical leader in several projects for a variety of customers. Among them, was the development of a new banking platform in Java (J2EE) to replace the aging, mainframe-based system. Also of note was an image-based (using an optical-flow algorithm), motion detection module for a proprietary mobile operating system. Spent some time in Gibraltar with a team to finish development, deployment of the customer's new platform in Ruby on Rails, as well as measuring performance and adding a caching layer (with Memcached) so that it would support an upcoming major sporting event.

#### 9. Media System, 2003 - 2004

Trainee. .NET desktop and mobile application development.

# Spoken Languages

- English (Advanced)
- Portuguese (Native)

### Certifications

- Sun Certified Java Programmer SCJP 5.0
- Cambridge FSOL FCE University of Cambridge

#### Skills

- Cloud: AWS, Google Cloud, Azure
- Containerization: Kubernetes, Docker, familiar with many CNCF projects
- Devops: Terraform, Ansible, Chef, Packer, Consul, Vault, Prometheus
- Web technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React
- Oracle Technologies: (Java Platform including J2SE, JEE, and J2ME)

Stephen Pedrosa Eilert

- Extensive Linux knowledge.
- Source Control: Git, Mercurial, SVN
- Programming Languages: Python, Go, C, C++, Java, C#, Javascript, Ruby, Lua, Objective-C, Scheme
- Database Management Systems: PostgreSQL, MySQL
- NoSQL databases: Cassandra, Kafka, Redis, Memcachedb, Elasticsearch
- Mobile Development: some Android, heavy focus on iOS
- Microsoft Technologies: (.NET Framework, Win32 API, SQL Server, Team Foundation Server, PowerShell)

Last updated: January 25, 2022 http://github.com/outworlder/CV.git/